talktofrank.com 2012-11-06

# Cookie policy | FRANK

Last updated: 25th May 2012

This page explains what you need to know about how talktofrank.com uses cookies on its website and how to manage or remove them if you wish to do so.

**What are cookies?**

A cookie is a small amount of data sent to your computer or mobile phone from a website.  This means the website can recognize your device (your computer or mobile phone) if you return to the same site.  Cookies cannot be used to identify you personally. 

A cookie often includes a unique identifier, which is a randomly generated number.  This is stored on your device’s hard drive.  Many cookies are automatically deleted after you finish using the website.

Cookies are not programs and do not collect information from your device.

Cookies make your experience of using websites faster and easier. They allow websites to create a customised view of pages to which you navigate. For example, they are commonly used to authenticate or identify registered users of a website without requiring them to sign in each time they access it. Other uses include maintaining a ‘shopping basket’ of goods a user has chosen to purchase, site personalisation (presenting different pages to different users) and tracking the pages a user has visited on a site for analysis purposes.

Cookies may come with or without an expiry date. Cookies without an expiry date exist until the browser is closed, while cookies with an expiry date may be stored by the device until the expiry date passes.

You can restrict or block cookies set by FRANK  but this may limit your use of some functionality.

FRANK uses third-party suppliers who also set cookies on our behalf to deliver the services that record usage and monitor advertising. More information on the cookies set by FRANK and its third-party suppliers can be found below.

**How to manage your cookies**

Cookies are sent to your browser (whether you use Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Safari or any other browser) by a website and then stored in the cookies directory of your device.

To check and update your cookies settings, you will need to know what browser you are using and what version of it you have. You can usually find this out by opening the browser (just as though you were going to use the internet) and then clicking on 'Help' and then 'About'. This will give you information about the browser version you are using.

To find out how to allow, block, delete and manage the cookies on all standard web browsers, go to [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) and select the browser and version you are using. You'll also find information about how to delete cookies from your computer.

If you use a mobile phone to browse [www.talktofrank.com](http://www.talktofrank.com/) or other sites that use cookies, please refer to your handset manual for guidance.

**1\. 'First-party' cookies**

First-party cookies are set and controlled by FRANK. Each of these is listed below, with a description of its purpose and benefit.

  * Javascript set
  * 12 Months
  * This lets FRANK know if you have previously voted for a user story as 'helpful'.

  * Javascript set
  * When you close your browser
  * This is a temporary cookie used to activate a thank you message after you have voted a user story as 'helpful'.

  * has_js
  * When you close your browser
  * Used to determine if your device has Javascript enabled or not as this affects the interface that is shown.

**2.   ‘Third-party cookies’**

Third-party cookies are not set directly by talktofrank.com, but by third-party service or functionality providers.

For more information about the cookies used by these suppliers, including how to opt-out, you will need to view their individual privacy policies. Managing, deleting or blocking these cookies requires you to visit the websites of these third parties or to adjust your browser’s cookie controls accordingly.

The third-party cookies used by talktofrank.com are described here, with the purpose and benefit of each and a link to the third-party’s cookies information or privacy policy.

**Google Analytics cookies**

These cookies help FRANK to understand what areas of the site are popular and unpopular, so we can improve the service you receive and archive what is not used.

Google Analytics stores the information collected by the cookie on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf.

Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google

**_How to reject or delete this kind of cookie:_**

<http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacypolicy.html>

  * _utma
  * 2 years
  * This keeps track of the number of times a visitor has been to the site, when their first visit was, and when their last visit occurred

  * _utmb
  * 30 mins
  * A timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor enters the site

  * _utmc
  * End of session
  * A timestamp of the exact moment in time when a visitor leaves the site - having waited 30 minutes for another pageview to happen, and if it doesn’t, it expires

  * _utmz
  * 6 months
  * This keeps track of where the visitor came from, what search engine was used, what link was clicked on, what keywords used, and where in the world the site was accessed from

**Doubleclick cookies**

The advertisements that drive traffic to talktofrank.com (when shown) are served by a third-party ad serving provider called DoubleClick. The cookies accompanying the ads allow monitoring of the effectiveness of the ads (e.g. by using statistical analysis cookies) and make the ads more relevant to you.

**_How to reject or delete this kind of cookie:_**

<http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/index.aspx>

  * test_cookie
  * 1 second
  * This cookie is added and removed straight away to test if the user's browser supports cookies.

  * id
  * 2 years
  * Unique cookie code to determine which advertisements have been shown to your device through the Doubleclick system. Allows effectiveness-monitoring of the advertisements.

**AppNexus/Adnxs cookies**

The advertisements that drive traffic to talktofrank.com (when shown) are served by a third-party ad serving provider called Adnxs. The cookies accompanying the ads allow monitoring of the effectiveness of the ads (e.g. by using statistical analysis cookies) and make the ads more relevant to you. 

**_How to reject or delete this kind of cookie:_**

<http://appnexus.com/platform-policy#choices>

  * sess
  * 12 months
  * These cookies collect non-personally identifiable information for analytics purposes and is related to session management.

  * uuid2
  * 15 months
  * These cookies collect non-personally identifiable information for analytics purposes.

**Adviva/SpecificMedia cookies**

The advertisements that drive traffic to talktofrank.com (when shown) are served by a third-party ad serving provider called SpecificMedia using their Adviva product. The cookies accompanying the ads allow monitoring of the effectiveness of the ads (e.g. by using statistical analysis cookies) and make the ads more relevant to you. 

**_How to reject or delete this kind of cookie:_**

<http://www.specificmedia.co.uk/privacy>

  * ug
  * 5 years
  * These cookies collect non-personally identifiable information for analytics purposes and is related to session management for advertisement display.

**Scorecard Research cookies**

The FAQ items on the talktofrank.com site have a “Did you find this helpful?” function. This cookie is used to track, in a non-personally identifiable way, if you have clicked this button and responded.  

**_How to reject or delete this kind of cookie:_**

<http://www.scorecardresearch.com/privacy.aspx>

  * UID
  * 2 years
  * These cookies collect non-personally identifiable information for analytics purposes.

  * UIDR
  * 2 years
  * These cookies collect non-personally identifiable information for analytics purposes.

**YouTube cookies**

YouTube is used to playback video content on the talktofrank site. YouTube uses session cookies to handle the display of full-screen video playback and this cookie is used to determine if you would see the old interface or the new interface for such playback.

**_How to reject or delete this kind of cookie:_**

<http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

  * VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE
  * 8 months
  * Remembers if YouTube should show new or old video-interface to you.

**GoogleMaps cookies**

Googlemaps is used on the talktofrank.site to provide mapping information for local services. A Javascript-set cookie is used for the creation and display of the interface for the maps. No personally-identifiable information is collected.

**_How to reject or delete this kind of cookie:_**

<http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

  * ug
  * 5 years
  * These cookies collect non-personally identifiable information for analytics purposes.
